

# JOSÉ M. DOMÍNGUEZ

ARCHITECT/SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

#### **PROFILE**

I'm a Spain-based (open to relocation on a global level) architect and software developer with 10 years of experience in digital fabrication, parametric modeling and complex geometry.

My main focus these days is combine my knowledge on parametric modeling and digital fabrication with the creation of innovative digital solutions through web development.

#### **DETAILS**

Nationality: Spanish Date of birth: 16/12/1989

Language: Spanish/English/Portuguese

#### LINKS

#### **Personal Website**

https://jmdevc.netlify.app/

#### Github

https://github.com/jmdc89

#### HOW TO REACH ME

Address: Seville(Spain) Cell: +34 647656094 Email: jmdevc@gmail.com

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Computational designer & digital engineering Sagrada Familia Temple(Barcelona) | 2019 -2020

Digital Fabrication Consulting/ Grasshopper and Rhinoceros trainer

2018 - 2019

Researcher(Aeronautical and bioprosthetic field)

Sao Paulo State University | 2014 - 2018

#### **EDUCATION**

#### FreeCodeCamp (2020/2021)

- Responsive Web Design Certification
- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Certification
- FrontEnd Development Libraries Certification

#### Bachelor in Architecture (2007/2014)

• Seville (Spain)

#### International Exchange Program(2013)

• Sao Paulo State University

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

#### **Conferences papers**

- Parametric design applied in the development of structures(Case study: bamboo spiral structure - Florianópolis(Brazil)
- Additive Manufacturing: Development of a prosthesis of a toucan's bill -California(United States)

#### SKILLS

#### 3D modeling

- · Rhinoceros 3D
- · Grasshopper 3D
- · Autodesk Fusion 360

#### Design

• Adobe Illustrator/Photoshop

#### 3D Printing

- Autodesk Meshmixer
- Simplify3d/Cura/Repetier
- Materialise Magics

#### CNC/Lasercut

- Esprit
- Aspire
- · Autodesk Fusion CAM

#### **Web Development**

- HTML/CSS
- JavaScript
- ReactJS
- GatsbyJS
- Three.js
- · Visual Studio/Github

## DIGITAL MANIFACTURING TECHNOLOGIES TRAINING

## Center for Advanced Product Development (2014-2018)

- Gom Atos 3D scanner system
- Zprinter 650 Plus 3dprinter
- Router CNC 3D Transform 2000/2
- 3D Zbuilder Ultra 3dprinter
- CNC Roland DX 540
- Lasercut Ecnc L1060
- Creality 3D Ender

# COMPLEMENTARY EDUCATION(COURSES)

## Udemy/SkillShare/Coursera/Youtube(2011 - 2021)

- Advanced Web Development
- Modern JavaScript
- Styled Components
- BootStrap
- React The complete guide
- GatsbyJS
- ThreeJS
- · Materialise Magics
- Python
- · Autodesk Meshmixer
- Parametric design for CNC
- Autodesk Revit
- Parametric environmental adaptive design (Ecotect, grasshopper + geko)
- Augmented Reality(Unity + Vuforia)
- Esprit CAM
- Autodesk Fusion 360
- Grasshopper and Firefly (Interactive systems using Arduino)

#### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

#### Trainings - Lynk3D(Brazil) - 2018/2019

- Autodesk Fusion 360
- Rhinoceros/Grasshopper3D

#### Workshops - SESC(Brazil) - 2017/2019

- · Advanced jewelry design
- 3d printing
- Lasercut
- Digital fabrication
- Introduction to CAD milling(Fusion 360)

#### Workshops - UNESP(Brazil) - 2013/2016

- Grasshopper + Firefly
- · Parametric design

### Workshop - University of Architecture Benito Juárez(Oaxaca, México) - 2014

Parametric design in Architecture